MICHAEL KAHANE

WWW.MICHAELKAHANE.COM • WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/MICHAELKAHANE MICHAELJKAHANE@GMAIL.COM

PROFILE

Developer and designer with work ranging from websites to mobile health platforms to creative digital installations to video games. Believes in user research/testing and using the right technology for the job, even if that means learning something new on a tight deadline. Passionate about work related to human rights, social justice, and open societies. Loves cats, making games, and trying new food.

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE CREATIVE TECHNOLOGIST

BROOKLYN, NY | 2017 - PRESENT

Offering creative technology design and development to clients such as 72andSunny and The International Center for Advocates Against Discrimination.

CREATIVE TECHNOLOGIST

RP3 AGENCY | WASHINGTON, DC | 2015 - 2016

Worked on a wide range of projects including websites, interactive installations, and games. Discovered how emerging technologies might provide innovative solutions to clients. Concepting, user experience, front-end development, iterative prototyping. Notable projects included a large kinetic scoreboard at the Washington Nationals stadium, a yeti snowball fight game for Google Cardboard, and website redesigns.

FELLOW IN INFORMATION DESIGN/ICT CONSULTANT OPEN SOCIETY FOUNDATIONS | NEW YORK, NY | 2013 - 2014

Developed an open source ICT system that allows indigenous Guatemalans to report to the Guatemalan government when medical supplies are low using SMS, Ushahidi, and custom PHP plugins. Traveled to Guatemala City in the summer of 2013 and winter of 2014 to work with the Center for Equity and Governance in Systems of Health (CEGSS) for user testing and further development. The

platform is now being used by the International Center for Advocates Against Discrimination in Assam, India.

GAME DESIGNER/DEVELOPER

FÚTBOL FOREVER | NEW YORK, NY | 2013 - PRESENT

Fútbol Forever is a wacky four player post-planetary soccer video game. Development began in C++, but ended in Unity with C# scripting. Fútbol Forever currently exists as an arcade cabinet as part of the Death By Audio Arcade, and has been exhibited at many galleries and events including the Smithsonian American Art Museum, MAGFest, and World Maker Faire.

ONLINE MEDIA SPECIALIST

MOVING MARYLAND FORWARD | TOWSON, MD | 2012

Developed written content for an online advocacy network funded by the Robert Deutsch Foundation designed to educate and engage Maryland residents in support of Maryland social justice issues.

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML, CSS, Sass, JS, P5.is, Three.is, React.is, Node.is, Git

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN

Sketch, InVision, Rapid Prototyping, User Scenarios, Wireframes

GAME DESIGN

Iterative Prototyping, Unity, C#, C++, VR

CREATIVE CODING

openFameworks (C++), Processing (Java), Physical Computing (Arduino)

EDUCATION

MFA DESIGN & TECHNOLOGY

Parsons the New School for Design | New York, NY \mid 2014 GPA: 3.89

BA ENGLISH LANGUAGE & LITERATURE

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND | COLLEGE PARK, MD | 2011 GPA: 3.91 (CUM LAUDE)

SELECTED PROJECTS

OPEN HEALTH NETWORKS

Open source ICT system that allows individuals to take a reporting folder to a health facility and send an SMS message consisting of codes to indicate on an online map (Ushahidi) which medical supplies are missing. JavaScript/PHP/MySQL.

FÚTBOL FOREVER

Fútbol Forever is a wacky four player post-planetary soccer video game. Long after the purge of Earth, humanity holds the pieces of its destroyed culture tightly. Now, on the brink of extinction with no home to return to, humanity must redefine itself. Though they need not start from scratch. They have Fútbol. Unity/C#.

GAME CENTRAL

A large, kinetic display that tracks scores and game statistics with model trains moving in real time. G-Scale model locomotives and different colored freight cars indicate balls, strikes, outs, base runners, and runs. Node.js/Arduino/Raspberry Pi